CURRICULUM VITAE

USHA TANEJA

C-69 First Floor Dayal Bagh Faridabad Haryana -121009 Email: 09ushataneja@gmail.com +919205768635

Professional Summary

I am excited to introduce myself as a seasoned professional with over 15 years of extensive experience in backend operations, specifically within the immigration industry. For the past 8 years, I have excelled in the documentation department as a dedicated Case Manager and Team Manager. My expertise lies in various aspects of Canadian Permanent Residency, including Express Entry, Provincial Nominee Programs (PNP), Educational Credential Assessment (ECA) filing, Job Bank procedures, and profile marketing. I have successfully managed client escalations, complaints, and refund cases with tact and efficiency while maintaining records of all client data.

Educational Qualifications

- Bachelor of Arts2006 Graduate from Deshbandhu College, New Delhi
- 12th Passed (CBSE)
 10th Passed (CBSE)
 2003 V.S. Sarvodaya Girls S S School No.1, New Delhi
 2001 V.S. Sarvodaya Girls S S School No.1, New Delhi

Academic Qualifications

• N.T.T (1 Year) 2004 South Delhi Polytechnic for Women, New Delhi

Computer Knowledge

- MS Office. Word, Excel, Outlook.
- Google Drive. Docs, Forms, Gmail, Sheets. Spreadsheet. Excel, Google drive
- Email. Outlook, Gmail, Filters, Folders

Work Experience

Have 15 years' professional experience, detailed as under:

Senior Case Manager – Wider World Immigration, Nehru Place from March 2024 to till date

- Client relationship management
- Prepare proposal documents to be sent to clients
- Handle escalations, refund claims and client complaints.
- Providing guidance to sales team on the process and procedures of immigration for respective country.
- Prepare PPT & Proposal emails as per the client requirement for all the programs.
- Initiate renewal of contracts on time.
- Meeting with agents for B2B
- Profile Marketing for AIP, RNIP & Carrier Assistance Program
 ECA filing WES, ICES, IQAS, CES, ICAS
- Filing Express Entry, Saskatchewan, Manitoba, PEI, New Brunswick, Arrima. Renew SLA After expiring the SLA convince to the client to renew the agreement.

Case Manager - Grades Global Immigration, Nehru Place from Dec' 2023 to Feb' 2024.

- Client relationship management
- Assist in business development activities by identifying potentials clients. Prepare proposal documents to be sent to clients
- Handle escalations, refund claims and client complaints.
- Providing guidance to junior team members on the process and procedures of immigration for respective country,
- Review and monitor the work carried out by team and ensure they meet the required quality standards of the firm.
- Prepare PPT & Proposal emails as per the client requirement for all the programs. Initiate renewal of contracts on time.
- Profile Marketing for AIP, RNIP & Carrier Assistance Program ECA filing WES, ICES, IQAS, CES, ICAS
- Filing Express Entry, Saskatchewan, Manitoba, PEI, New Brunswick, Arrima.
 Renew SLA After expiring the SLA convince to the client to renew the agreement.

Operations Manager – Global Choice Immigration, Nehru Place – March 2023- Sep 2023

- Client relationship management
- Train and manage team in Asia branches
- Assist in business development activities by identifying potentials clients. Prepare proposal documents to be sent to clients
- Prepare marketing material / Presentation for new business
- Share marketing & promotions ideas with seniors on how to increase productivity

follow up with clients to ensure invoice payments are made within the stipulated time. Providing guidance to junior team members on the process and procedures of immigration for respective country,

- Review and monitor the work carried out by team and ensure they meet the required quality standards of the firm.
- Handle escalation, refund claims and client complaint.
- Meeting with agents for B2B partnership
- Prepare emails for all the programs as per the client's requirement. Initiate renewal of contracts on time.

<u>Team Manager (Documentation Department- Countrywide Visas Pvt Ltd Nehru Place - June 2019 – Feb 2023</u>

- Team lead and manage operations
- Overseeing, training, or advising team members. Handle escalation, refund claims and client complaints
- Coordinate with clients and get prepared documents for visa file.
- Solve client queries, coordinate with client on call via email explain about the checklist and the process.
- Prepare work schedule for team members to work easily
- Check eligibility and prepare Technical Assessment Report for all programs
 Maintain record for client data and assign case
- Profile Marketing for AIP, RNIP & Carrier Assistance
 Program ECA filing WES, ICES, IQAS, CES, ICAS
- Filing Express Entry, Saskatchewan, Manitoba, PEI, New Brunswick, Arrima. Renew SLA – After expiring the SLA convince to the client to renew the agreement. Given business in every month, average 1 lac.

Case Officer | VMake Visas Nehru Place - June 2017 - June 2019

- Coordinate with client on call via email about the process queries
- Explain about the required documents (checklist)
- ECA filing WES, IQAS

Sales Consultant | More Visas Nehru Place - October 2016 - May 2017

Sales Consultant- call to the client and achieve the sales target

Customer Care Executive | Kestone IMS Pvt. Ltd Balaji Estate - December 2015 - August 2016

• Call candidate to explain about the event and confirm the presence of the the candidate

<u>Vac Coordinator - Backend | Green Dust Pvt Ltd</u> Chattarpur - April 2015 - November 2015

• Coordinate with warehouses for dispatch the product and given confirmation to the client about the product.

PRO, Online Sales Coordinator & Media Coordinator ACE Teleshop Pvt LtdC.R Park -September 2011 - April 2015

- <u>PRO</u> Coordinate with the agents and sell the product of teleshopping maintain record of sales and purchase.
- Online Sales Coordinator Work on the ecommerce site like, Paytm, eBay, Amazon, Snap deal, Greendust, Flip kart etc.
- Maintain the record of sales & return.
- Coordinate with client & warehouse
- Media Coordinator Coordinate with the media channel for schedule slot.

Team Leader | Best Bakers Pvt. Ltd Lajpat Nagar - February 2011 - September 2011

• Visit all the outlet of south Delhi, Faridabad & Gurgaon (Like Select City Walk, Ambience Mall, Spencer) for purchase order.

Sales Coordinator | Yakult Danone Pvt. Ltd Okhla Ph-1 - August 2009 - January 2011

• Sales Coordinator – Explore local markets, shops & residential area of Vasant Kunj to promote and sale the product "Yakult".

Tele Caller | Adroit Outsourcing Pvt. Ltd Sant Nagar - May 2006 - January 2009

Tele calling for credit card collection.

SKILSS

Team Lead | Customer Service | Product Knowledge | Sales & Marketing Scheduling | Creativity | Energetic | Hardworking | Punctual

Hobbies

Listening Music, Art & Craft

Personal Information

Date Of Birth 28.05.1985

Father's name Lt.Sh. Bhupinder Pal Taneja

Blood Group A+
Gender Female
Marital Status Unmarried
Nationality Indian

Language Known English, Hindi & Punjabi

I hereby declare and affirm that the above particulars furnished by me are true and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.

(Usha Taneja)

Place:

Faridabad 121009